Taufiiqul Hakim

Mobile Phone: +6282176350289 E-Mail: Taufiiqulhakim23@gmail.com

Website: taufik.netlify.app | github.com/taufik230301 | linkedin.com/in/taufiiqul-hakim/

Objective

I am a fresh graduate from State Polytechnic of Sriwijaya majoring in Computer Engineering that has experience in Information Technology, management, communication skills, language, writing, research, design graphic, and computer. I am ready for looking at new challenges and changes in the entry-level position Tech Industry. focused on fields that use logic and problem-solving skills. Certainly, I must have the ability to communicate, think creatively, collaborate in a team, and also be agile to learn new things.

Work Experience

CV Digital Creative, Palembang, Indonesia

July 2021 -

Now

Teaching Assistant

Core Responsibilities

- Being a Teaching Assistant in database analyst class to increase a student's comprehension of PostgreSQL
- Managed Scheduled, Tasks, and attendance for students, and was also active in sharing about how to design and also analyze the database's structure

Software Engineer Freelance

Core Responsibilities

- Handle Web-Based Projects from company clients, integrate API Applications to Web Apps
- Using some technology such as Codeigniter, Jquery, Javascript to satisfy clients request

Internship Experience

Sagara Technology Asia, Jakarta, Indonesia

Full-Stack Specialist Developer

September 2020 - January 2021

Core Responsibilities

- Maintained Teknologi.id website using Lumen Framework

PT. Citra Bumi Sumatera - Sumeks - Sumatera Ekspres, Palembang, Indonesia

Fullstack Developer

August 2020 - Okt 2020

Core Responsibilities

- Maintained and Developed a new feature in E-Paper Apps to expand the company's target market
- Integrate data from Mobile Apps to consume data from Website API

Volunteer Experience

Palembang Digital Community, Palembang, Indonesia

Front - End Developer

March 2020 - March 2021

- Core Responsibilities
 - Optimized Web Front-End Efficiency to reduce data usage in users UI
 - Collaborate with UI/UX Designer to accomplish the best practice of Web Apps Design

Education

State Polytechnic of Sriwijaya, Palembang, Indonesia

August 2018 - August 2021

A. Md. T.(3.14/4.0)

Related Course: Computer Engineering

General Qualification

- Experienced in research Information Technology, and have basic fundamentals in computer science such as DSA, OOP, Functional Programming, and Procedural Programming.
- Have Good Marketing, Management, and Leadership skills in entry-level position Tech Industry
- Have Basics Knowledge in Apps Development, Web Development, Database Analyst, HTML, CSS, PHP, Python, SQL, Javascript, MYSQL, PostgreSQL, and Github
- Good in Indonesian Both oral and Written, English Limited Working Proficiency
- have good communication skills and eager to adapt

Related Activity

 Perhimpunan Mahasiswa Informatika dan Komputer Nasional Sekretaris Bidang Kominfo July 2018 - Now

- Developer Student Club

March 2020 - July 2021

Core Team

September 2020 – January 2021

- Generasi Baru Bank Indonesia

August 2018 - August 2021

Anggota Divisi Kerja Sama
- Himpunan Mahasiswa Jurusan Teknik Komputer Anggota Humas

References

- Malian Zikri, CEO Digital Creative, Sriwijaya University(malianzikri92@gmail.com)
- Areif Rahmansyah, Machine Learning Engineer Gojek, Sriwijaya University(ariefrahmansyah@hotmail.com)

Portofolio

- Palembang Digital Community Website

Palembang Digital Community has the vision to create Talented IT Resources that can compete for the excellent digital field, I've Responsibility for developing the Website Front-end and also Optimize its users' data usage, I Collaborate with UI/UX Designer to accomplish the best practice of Web Apps Design. Using javascript programming language with React JS framework to handle the interactive User-interface Website and also to reduce data usage for the user to access the web front-end more efficiently.

- Infographic Website Balai Jasa Konstruksi 2 Palembang

Build Interactive Infographic Website using Jquery Library, Integrate Golang API to Codeigniter 3, make Infographic data insightful for the user. make dynamic datasets using chart js library, manipulate JSON data from API and integrate them to Chart js Library. Users can download a file based on chart data and also capture it in PNG when the user needs the data from the chart.

Application Of Guidance Management Final Report For Student Department Of Computer Engineering
 This application is an application that can assist the final paper guidance process, with the aim of making
 it easier for students to carry out guidance between students and lecturers when performing the guidance
 process for the final paper. Making this application uses the text editor Visual Studio Code, using the PHP
 programming language and the framework Codeigniter, while the database uses the MYSQL database.

- Curitter Web Apps

Curitter is a website where you can find all information about doctors' practice schedules and online registration places from all hospitals in Palembang. In addition, you can also see various kinds of health articles that can help you improve your health independently. Using PHP programming language to handle the data from the MYSQL database, for the framework I Used Codeigniter to make more sustainable development.

E-Paper For Sumatera Ekspress

I've responsible for building online paper store Apps and maintenance technical support, in Front-End, Back-end Mobile Development, I built an android application for an electronic paper that uses API to consume the data from the database. Using Flutter Framework to Build Interactive User Interface for Mobile Apps, Integrated the data from a website to our Mobile Apps that use JSON to parse the data.